<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode 
		icon="./shapefilesAsWKT.png"  
		type="Other" 
		xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" 
		xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
		xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
		
    <name>Geocode Address (OpenStreetMap)</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Create a Point Geometry from an Address (OpenStreetMap)
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        Geocoding is the process of converting addresses 
        (like "1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA") 
        into geographic coordinates (like latitude 37.423021 and longitude -122.083739).
        <p>
        For a given column containing an address, this node will iterate every row of the input
        table, and call the OpenStreetMap Geocoding API (aka <a href="https://nominatim.openstreetmap.org/">Nominatim</a>) for each address. 
        The execution might be slow, as one network query is done for each line of the table; 
        note you obviously need a network access to use this API. 
        </p>
        <p>
        Please read the <a href="https://operations.osmfoundation.org/policies/nominatim/">Usage Policy</a> of Nominatim 
        which publishes the Open Street Map API, and ensure your usage complies with it. 
        This service runs on donated servers which are not supposed to be used to geocode large
        sets of data. According to these terms of service:
        <ul>
        <li>Maximum one request per second can be done; we enforce this limit; this means
        60 rows require a minute; 600 rows take 10 minutes; 3600 rows require one hour.</li>
        <li>The queries are cached on your hard drive; so running 2 times the same query
        will always return the same result (the second time will be way quicker).</li>
		<li>You should not execute several instances of this node in parallel in order
		to avoid overloading the Nominatim servers.</li>
        </ul>
        </p>
        <p>
        In case several possibilities are returned by the OSM Geocoding API, 
        one line will be created for each possibility. A warning will be displayed in this case.
        You can easily use a row filter to keep only the type of result you are interested in
         (such as residential), or use a "group by" node in order to keep only one result by geometry.
        </p>
        <p>
        The resulting table contains the original columns plus:
        <ul>
        <li><b>the_geom</b>: the geometry encoded in WKT (by default, a Point). The Coordinate Reference System is stored as a property of this column.</li>
        <li><b>type:</b> the type of place identified by OpenStreetMap, such as "residential", "living street", "service" or many other values</li>
        <li><b>osm id</b>: the id of this location for OpenStreetMap. Might be used to query more information from OpenStreetMap</li>
        <li><b>osm type:</b> an OpenStreetMap geometry is either a Node (point in space), Way (linear features and area boundaries) or a Relation (sometimes used to explain how other elements work together).
        See the <a href="https://wiki.openstreetmap.org/wiki/Elements">related doc</a> for more details.</li>
        <li><b>license:</b> the license under which the data was provided to</li>
        <li><b>rank:</b>the internal OpenStreetMap rank for this feature. It somehow corresponds spatial granularity</li>
        <li><b>rank interpretation:</b>a string interpretation of the rank of this feature according to the <a href="https://wiki.openstreetmap.org/wiki/Nominatim/Development_overview">OpenStreetMap documentation</a>:
        which states for instance that a country is ranked 16 whilst a House or building is 28. This interpretation is temptative, as OpenStreetMap states it might change from one country to another.
        Yet this facilitates the interpretation of the quality of the result: if you try to geocode houses locations, but only find street level rank, you better check manually if your houses are located 
        to the street only or at the actual house level.
        </li>
        </ul>
        </p>
        
        </intro>
        
        <option name="Column name address">Name of the column containing the address</option>
        <option name="Your email">Your email. Required by the term of service of Nominatim. 
        In case their servers would be overloaded by your requests, they would contact you there to discuss.
        Please always provide one.</option>
        <option name="service URL">The server which will be contacted for geocoding. 
        Change it if you want to use another Nominatim server (maybe your own instance you
        run one your own computer)</option>
        <option name="Fetch full geometries">If checked, will produce the full geometries from OpenStreetMap (such as polygon, linestring, etc.) 
        instead of a Point with x and y coordinates. Unfortunately, this produces heterogeneous geometry types which can not be easily viewed 
        nor stored into shapefiles. For instance a House which is precisely known might return the 
        polygon of the building's footprint, whilst a house number mapped to a street will 
        return the segment of the street of interest.
        </option>
        
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="table with addresses">A table to geocode</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="table with geocoded addresses">The table with geocoding information</outPort>
    </ports>    

</knimeNode>
