<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode 
		icon="./shapefilesAsWKT.png"  
		type="Other" 
		xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" 
		xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
		xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
		
    <name>Geocode Address (Google)</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Create a Point Geometry from an Address (Google)
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        Geocoding is the process of converting addresses 
        (like "1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA") 
        into geographic coordinates (like latitude 37.423021 and longitude -122.083739).
        These coordinates are produced as 2D Point Geometries. 
        <p>
        For a given column containing an address, this node will iterate every row of the input
        table, and call the <a href="https://developers.google.com/maps/documentation/geocoding/intro">Google Geocoding API</a> for each address. 
        The execution might be slow, as one network query is done for each line of the table; 
        note you obviously need a network access to use this node.
        Geocoding a large table might require a lot of time.
        </p>
        <p>
        In order to use the Google Geocoding API, you have 
        to <a href="https://developers.google.com/maps/documentation/geocoding/start#get-a-key">get a Google API key</a>
        and paste in into the Configuration pane. You probably will have to activate billing on your Google account; 
        to activate the Google Geocoding API in your developer dashboard; to increase the quota for this API to thousands;
        to reduce the quota per minute and day from unlimited to thousands. 
        Note that <b>numerous queries might lead to billing from Google</b>; 
        check the <a href="https://developers.google.com/maps/documentation/geocoding/usage-and-billing">billing conditions</a>.
        Remember that sharing a workflow in which you pasted your API key might lead other people to run queries in your name,
        leading to your account being billed by Google. 
        Also ensure you comply the <a href="https://developers.google.com/maps/documentation/geocoding/policies">Google Geocoding policies</a>.
        </p>
       
        <p>
        Several columns are created which contain the information returned by the API.
        <ul>
        <li><b>is partial</b>: if true, indicates that the geocoder did not return 
        an exact match for the original request, though it was able to match part of the 
        requested address. You may wish to examine the original request for misspellings and/or 
        an incomplete address. Partial matches most often occur for street addresses that do 
        not exist within the locality you pass in the request. Partial matches may also be 
        returned when a request matches two or more locations in the same locality. 
        For example, "21 Henr St, Bristol, UK" will return a partial match for both 
        Henry Street and Henrietta Street. Note that if a request includes a misspelled address 
        component, the geocoding service may suggest an alternative address. 
        Suggestions triggered in this way will also be marked as a partial match.
		</li>
        <li><b>type</b>: 
	        "ROOFTOP" indicates that the returned result is a precise geocode for which we have location information accurate down to street address precision.
			"RANGE_INTERPOLATED" indicates that the returned result reflects an approximation (usually on a road) interpolated between two precise points (such as intersections). Interpolated results are generally returned when rooftop geocodes are unavailable for a street address.
			"GEOMETRIC_CENTER" indicates that the returned result is the geometric center of a result such as a polyline (for example, a street) or polygon (region).
			"APPROXIMATE" indicates that the returned result is approximate.</li>
        <li><b>location type</b>: a list which indicates the type of the returned result. 
	        This array contains a set of zero or more tags identifying the type of feature 
	        returned in the result. 
	        For example, a geocode of "Chicago" returns "locality" which indicates that "Chicago" is a 
	        city, and also returns "political" which indicates it is a political entity.
        </li>
        <li><b>place_id</b> is a unique identifier that can be used with other Google APIs. 
        For example, you can use the place_id in a <a href="https://developers.google.com/places/web-service/intro">Places API</a> request to 
        get details of a local business, such as phone number, opening hours, user reviews, and more.
        </li>
        </ul>
        You can get more information about the results returned by 
        Google Geocoding API by checking <a href="https://developers.google.com/maps/documentation/geocoding/start">their documentation</a>.
        </p>
        <p>
        In order to save time and quota (and money), the results from the calls are cached in your hard drive. 
        As a consequence, asking several times for the very same address in the same computer will not lead to more calls. 
        </p>
        <p>
        In case several possibilities are returned by the Google Geocoding API, 
        one line will be created for each possibility. A warning will be displayed in this case.
        </p>
                
        </intro>
        
        <option name="Column name address">Name of the column containing the address</option>
        <option name="API Key">Key for Google API to use for geocoding</option>

    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="table with addresses">A table to geocode</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="table with geocoded addresses">The table with geocoding information</outPort>
    </ports>    

</knimeNode>
