<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode 
		icon="./shp-wkt-reader-icon.png" 
		type="Source" 
		xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" 
		xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
		xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
		
    <name>Read from GeoTIFF</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Reads Spatial Data from GeoTIFF format
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        <p>
        Reads spatial data stored in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GeoTIFF">GeoTIFF format</a>. 
        Decodes every attribute of the spatial features as a column of a corresponding KNIME type.
        </p>
        <p>
		GeoTIFF is raster, or coverage, data. 
		We produce a table with (according to options) the row id, the x/y coordinates of the cell.
		You miqht also create a vector polygon for every pixel (slower). 
		Every band in the GeoTIFF file is extracted as a columns. Types are detected automatically. 
		Column namer are the names of the bands in the file.
        </p>
        <p>
        Several variables are also produced with metadata such as the coordinate reference system, the pixel size or the bounding box. 
        </p>
        <p>
        The actual decoding of the shapefile format is done using the <a href="https://geotools.org/">geotools library</a>.
       	The support of GeoTIFF is unsupported in GeoTools, so this node might work in most cases but not support the full GeoJSON format.
        </p>
        
        </intro>
        
        <option name="Selected file">The KML to open (often finishing with .kml)</option>
       
        <option name="Create a column for ID">Create a column with the index of the pixel (first is 0, the first one right is 1, etc)</option>
        <option name="Create columns with line/column">Create columns for the x/y coordinates in the cell (not latitude / longitude)</option>
        <option name="Create a column for the geometry">Create a column with a vector geometry (slower)</option>
        <option name="Create columns with latitude/longitude">Create columns with the latitude/longitude of the centroid of the pixel (slower)</option>
        
        <option name="Selected file">The KML to open (often finishing with .kml)</option>
       
      
       
      	<option name="Detect masked values">Consider the values at lower infinity as being masked (slows down reading, but reduces the volume of data produced)</option>     
       	<option name="Skip rows when all values are missing">When all bands are detected missing, skip the row (might save space)</option>
       
       
       
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>        
        <outPort index="0" name="WKT entities">The population with their attributes and WKT representation.</outPort>
    </ports>    
  
</knimeNode>
