<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode 
		icon="./shp-wkt-reader-icon.png" 
		type="Source" 
		xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" 
		xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
		xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
		
    <name>Read from GML</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Reads Spatial Data from GML format
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        <p>
        Reads spatial data stored in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Geography_Markup_Language">Geography Markup Language (GML) format</a>
        and decodes the geometries into <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Well-known_text_representation_of_geometry">WKT (Well-known Text Representation)</a>. 
        Decodes every attribute of the spatial features as a column of a corresponding KNIME type.
        </p>
        <p>
        Note that KML data is always assumed to be encoded in the Coordinate Reference System EPSG:4326. 
        If you have problems with further processing of spatial data, you might try to reproject to another 
        CRS using the "Reproject WKT geometries" node.
        </p>
        <p>
        GML is a complex format; it is not a totally defined format, but more a family of formats which can be tuned 
        by schemas. There is no reference validation tool for developers to ensure their code writes or reads these
        formats properly. As a consequence, writing and reading GML features remain an uncertain experience. 
        </p>
        <p>
        The actual decoding of the GML format is done by the <a href="https://geotools.org/">geotools library</a>.
        </p>
        
        </intro>
        
        <option name="Selected file">The GML to open (often finishing with .gml)</option>
        <option name="skip standard columns">Skip the columns which are automatically created by the underlying library 
	        and are most of the time useless ("bounded by", "description", "name"). Uncheck if one column of interest to you
	        does not appear after reading.</option>
        
       
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>        
        <outPort index="0" name="WKT entities">The population with their attributes and WKT representation.</outPort>
    </ports>    
  
</knimeNode>
