<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode 
		icon="./shp-wkt-reader-icon.png" 
		type="Source" 
		xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" 
		xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
		xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
    
    <name>Read Spatial from Shapefile</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Reads spatial features (geometries) from a Shapefile. 
        Accepts any geometry type: points, lines, or polygons.
        Decodes the geometry as a String column in WKT (Well-known Text Representation).
        Decodes every attribute of the spatial features as a column of a corresponding KNIME type. 
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        Reads spatial features (geometries) from a shapefile. 
        
        <p>
        Accepts any geometry type: points, lines, polygons, multilines, multipolygons, etc. 
        Decodes the geometry as a String column in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Well-known_text_representation_of_geometry">WKT (Well-known Text Representation)</a>. 
        Decodes every attribute of the spatial features as a column of a corresponding KNIME type.
        </p>
        <p>
        In the resulting table, a line is created for each spatial feature. 
        A string column "the_geom" contains the geometry in <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Well-known_text_representation_of_geometry">WKT (Well-known Text Representation)</a>.
        Each other attribute in the shapefile is mapped to a KNIME type: if a column in an integer in the shapefile, it will be translated as an integer (same for double, Boolean, long, string).
        </p>
        <p>
        A property "crs WKT" is sent along with the result which contains the description of the Coordinate Reference System read in the shapefile (if any).
        </p>
        <p>
        The actual decoding of the shapefile format is done using the <a href="https://geotools.org/">geotools library</a>.
        </p>

		</intro>
        
        <option name="Selected file">The shapefile to open (often finishing with .shp)</option>
        <option name="encoding">
        	The encoding used to encode accents and other special characters in the file. 
        	Is UTF8 by default. 
        	Change it if you have problems with accents and special characters. 
       	</option>
        
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <outPort index="0" name="WKT entities">The population with their attributes and WKT representation.</outPort>
    </ports>
    
</knimeNode>
